Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Records on Microfilm 5976 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Membership Ledgers; General Files (American Train Dispatchers Association-Extra Porters) (Reel 28)
  - 0652. Colored Locomotive Firemen's Conference. 4 pages., 1958; 19 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Notice of 1958 Conference of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Provisional Committee for the Organization of Colored Locomotive Firemen.
  - 0656. Congress of Industrial Organizations - Pullman Porters' Organizing Committee. 3 pages., 1946; 20 (Reel 28)
  - 0659. Congress of Industrial Organizations - Libel Suit Against. 24 pages., 1949; 21 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Proposed settlement in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Congress of Industrial Organizations libel suits.
  - 0683. Constitution - Joint American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations. 8 pages., 1955; 22 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Amendments to articles of proposed American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations constitution.
  - 0691. Constitution - Revision of (International). 28 pages., 1955; 23 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Amendments to Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution
  - 0719. Constitution - Revision of (Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters). 169 pages., 1956; 24 (Reel 28)
    Major Topics: Revision of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution and general rules; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters death benefits; rules and regulations governing the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Auditing Department; resolutions at the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters First and Second Triennial Conventions; Canadian Pacific Railroad Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters membership.
  - 0888. Delinquent Membership Dues. 27 pages., 1964-1970; 25 (Reel 28)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters demands for discharge of members for nonpayment of dues; dues collection; amendment of vacation agreement.
  - 0915. Department of State. 78 pages., 1951; 26 (Reel 28)
    Major Topics: Economic survey of life in the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (USSR); Congress of Industrial Organizations call for price ceilings and rent control; United States overseas information and educational exchange programs; report of meeting between the Assistant Secretary of State for Public Affairs and representatives of American trade unions; report on conditions of Hungarian workers; labor unions' position on the Korean War.
  - 0993. Earnings of Extra Employees (Chicago Central Division). 18 pages., 1953; 27 (Reel 28)
  - 1011. Earnings of Extra Employees (Chicago Commissary District). 19 pages., 1953; 28 (Reel 28)
  - 1030. Earnings of Extra Employees (Chicago Northern District). 50 pages., 1953; 29 (Reel 28)
  - 1080. Earnings of Extra Employees (Omaha). 5 pages., 1954; 30 (Reel 28)
    March 1954.
  - 1085. Eastern Zone Regional Conference. 6 pages., 1961; 31 (Reel 28)
    Major Topic: Arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Eastern Regional Zone Conference.
  - 1091. Extra Porter Salaries. 16 pages., 1959; 32 (Reel 28)
  - 1107. Extra Porters - Layovers (Unemployment Insurance Act). 94 pages., 1953; 33 (Reel 28)
    Major Topics: Claims for unemployment insurance benefits by extra porters; eligibility of retired men for unemployment insurance benefits; claims for unemployment benefits for layover days.
- General Files (Financial System-Railway Labor Executives Association) (Reel 29)
  - 0001. New Financial System (New York Office). 5 pages., 1952; 1 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Institution of new bookkeeping system at the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters New York Office. August 1952
  - 0006. Financing Railroad Equipment - Creation of Governmental Agency (Eastern Railroads). 6 pages., 1957; 2 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Proposed creation of governmental agency for financing railroad equipment.
  - 0012. Financing Railroads by the Government. 10 pages., 1957; 3 (Reel 29)
    Major Topics: Mediation agreement between the Eastern and Western Carriers' Conference Committees and their employees represented by the Railroad Yardmasters of America regarding wage increases and cost of living adjustments; proposed creation of governmental agency for financing railroad equipment.
  - 0022. Financial Report - Chicago Division (United States Department of Labor). 56 pages., 1960; 4 (Reel 29)
    Major Topics: Financial report for the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division filed under the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters income tax return.
  - 0078. Financial Reports - Chicago Zone (United States Labor Department and United States Treasury Department). 8 pages., 1963; 5 (Reel 29)
    Major Topics: Financial Reports filed by the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters' Denver, Kansas City, Omaha, and Twin Cities Divisions. July 31, 1963.
  - 0086. Financial Report (United States Department of Labor). 14 pages., 1962; 6 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Financial report filed by the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters' Denver, Kansas City, Omaha, and Twin Cities Division. July 31, 1962.
  - 0100. Financial Report - Midwest Zone (United States Department of Labor). 2 pages., 1963; 7 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Financial report of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters' Twin Cities Division.
  - 0102. Griffin-Landrum Bill (Section by Section Analysis). 70 pages., 1959; 8 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Analysis of the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (Griffin-Landrum Bill).
  - 0172. Griffin-Landrum Bill. 3 pages., 1959; 9 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters opposition to the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (Griffin-Landrum Bill).
  - 0175. Groups, Hospital, and Surgical Insurance (for Retired Non-Operating Railroad Employees and Their Dependents). 10 pages., 10 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Information on group hospital and surgical insurance for retired nonoperating railroad employees and their dependents. No date.
  - 0185. Group Insurance - Organizations. 8 pages., 1961; 11 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Information on Travelers group insurance policy for various labor unions.
  - 0193. Group Insurance Contract GA-23000. 10 pages., 1961; 12 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Group insurance contract for employees of the Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul and Pacific Railroad.
  - 0203. Health and Welfare (Mr. Leighty's Letter). 7 pages., 1957; 13 (Reel 29)
    Major Topics: Group insurance benefits for employee's dependents; report on Travelers group insurance policy for various labor unions.
  - 0210. Gratuities and Social Security (Hotel and Restaurant Employees). 4 pages., 1960; 14 (Reel 29)
    Major Topics: Relation of tips to wages in the computation of pension rights; resolutions of gratuities and Social Security adopted at the American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Third Constitutional Convention.
  - 0214. Income of Locals in Chicago-Midwest Zone. 2 pages., 1960; 15 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Instructions applicable to bonding of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters officials.
  - 0216. Income Tax. 11 pages., 1957; 16 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Income tax return for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division.
  - 0227. Income Tax Analysis (Regarding Tips for Porters). 8 pages., 1946; 17 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Information regarding payment of income tax on tips to porters.
  - 0235. Income Tax for Porters. 11 pages., 1957; 18 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Information on income tax owed by porters.
  - 0246. Income Tax on Porters' Tips. 3 pages., 1949; 19 (Reel 29)
  - 0249. Income Tax of Porters. 4 pages., 1956; 20 (Reel 29)
  - 0253. Income Tax Report - Chicago Division. 31 pages., 1955; 21 (Reel 29)
  - 0284. Income Tax Report - Chicago Division. 11 pages., 1958; 22 (Reel 29)
  - 0295. Income Tax Report - Chicago Division. 4 pages., 1960; 23 (Reel 29)
  - 0299. Income Tax Report - Chicago Division, January 10July 31, 1961. 5 pages., 24 (Reel 29)
  - 0304. Income Tax - traveling Expenses (ruling by Internal Revenue). 8 pages., 1958; 25 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Internal Revenue Service regulations on the reporting and substantiation of travel and other business expenses by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters employees.
  - 0312. International Association of Railway Employees (Merger). 9 pages., 1961; 26 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Report on the merger of the Colored Trainmen of America, the International Association of Railway Employees, and the Association of Railway Trainmen and Locomotive Firemen.
  - 0321. Joint Council Dining Car Employees Proposals for 25 Cent Per Hour Increase, Time and One Half, Paid Holidays. 21 pages., 1956; 27 (Reel 29)
  - 0342. Joint Council Controversy. 21 pages., 1961; 28 (Reel 29)
    Major Topics: Duties performed by waiter-coach attendants on Florida trains; elimination of chair car porters on the Fort Worth and Denver Railway; alleged Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters raids on the jurisdiction of the Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union.
  - 0363. Joint Council Propaganda. 108 pages., 1961; 29 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Propaganda issued by the Joint Council Dining Car Employees union.
  - 0471. Labor Bill (Presented in Senate). 39 pages., 1959; 30 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959. April 25, 1959.
  - 0510. Labor Organization. 7 pages., 1963-1964; 31 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Labor organization annual reports on the Denver and Chicago Divisions of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters.
  - 0517. Lathers' Case Decree. 18 pages., 1958; 32 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Decision in racial discrimination case against the Wood, Wire, and Metal Lathers International Union in the Chicago area.
  - 0535. Lease with Continental Properties, Incorporated (Signed 1952). 44 pages., 33 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Lease for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters office space in Chicago.
  - 0579. National Labor Relations Act - Union Representatives Going in Company Yard. 7 pages., 34 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Terms of the National Labor Relations Act dealing with employee rights and unfair labor practices. Undated.
  - 0586. Lie Detector Tests. 10 pages., 1953; 35 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Report on the admissibility of the results of lie detector tests in criminal courts.
  - 0596. Newspaper Clippings. 41 pages., 1956; 36 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Clippings relating to activities of railroad unions and racial discrimination by unions.
  - 0637. Newspaper Clippings. 66 pages., 1950-1962; 37 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Activities of Railroad unions and racial discrimination by unions. 1950-1951 [1958-1962]
  - 0703. Petition (Discharge of Brother Grooms). 160 pages., 1954; 38 (Reel 29)
    Major Topics: Dispute between Milton Webster and C.E. Grooms; dismissal of C.E. Grooms as second vice president of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division; request for hearing by A. Philip Randolph regarding the Grooms case.
  - 0863. Railroad Adjustment Board. 22 pages., 1957; 39 (Reel 29)
    Major Topics: Procedures to be followed in presentation of disputes before Third Division of the National Railroad Adjustment Board; status of dockets before Third Division of the National Railroad Adjustment Board.
  - 0885. Railroad Discharge Forms. 2 pages., 1965; 40 (Reel 29)
  - 0887. Railroad Retirement Act - Status of Original Employees Under. 11 pages., 1955; 41 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Unemployment insurance and sick benefits for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters employees in Canada.
  - 0898. Railway Labor Executive Association (Application for Membership). 7 pages., 1950-1951; 42 (Reel 29)
    Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters request for membership in the Railway Labor Executives Association.
  - 0905. Railway Labor Executives Association. 344 pages., 1951; 43 (Reel 29)
    Major Topics: Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union decision not to participate In the Joint National Railroad Adjustment Board Fund; Railway Labor Executives Association activities; agenda and minutes of Railway Labor Executives Association meetings; liberalization of pass regulations; list of chief executives and members of the Railway Labor Executives Association; amendment of Railroad Retirement Act and Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act; railroad safety.
- General Files (Rate of Pay-Workmen's Compensation Act); Personal Injury Claims; National Association for the Advancement of Colored Peoples; A. Philip Randolph Institute (Reel 30)
  - 0001. Rat of Pay. 3 pages., 1951; 1 (Reel 30)
    Major Topic: Pay rates for Pullman porters.
  - 0004. Resolution 46. 2 pages., 1953; 2 (Reel 30)
    Major Topic: Proposed increase in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters dues.
  - 0006. Rules Governing Monthly Reports of Railroad Accidents (Interstate Commerce Defense). 8 pages., 1957; 3 (Reel 30)
  - 0014. Rump Meetings (Bulletin-APR). 9 pages., 1955; 4 (Reel 30)
    Major topics: Condemnation of rump meetings of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters international and local officials by A, Philip Randolph; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters bulletin regarding unauthorized circulation of petitions.
  - 0023. Southwestern Zone Conference (Houston, Texas). 32 pages., 1949; 5 (Reel 30)
    Major Topics: Agenda and program for Southwestern Zone Conference; proper interpretation and application of rules in Pullman Company agreement. April 1949
  - 0055. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Strike Instructions. 4 pages., 1963; 6 (Reel 30)
  - 0059. Train Porters (Organization of). 82 pages., 1940; 7 (Reel 30)
    Major Topics: Mediation agreement between the Trainmen, Brakemen, and Porters Union, American Federation of Labor, and the Saint Louis and San Francisco Railroad Company; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters granted jurisdiction over train porters by the American Federation of Labor; membership of train porters union; proposals for basic month and wage increase for porters; labor relations law and the Negro worker.
  - 0141. Travelers Insurance Company. 6 pages, 1957; 8 (Reel 30)
    Major Topic: Medical claims filed with the Travelers Insurance Company.
  - 0147. Travelers Insurance Plan. 12 pages., 1957; 9 (Reel 30)
    Major Topic: Travelers Insurance Company group hospital and surgical plan.
  - 0159. Unemployment Insurance Benefits for Retired Men (Bulletin-APR). 4 pages., 1955; 10 (Reel 30)
    Major Topic: Eligibility of retired men for unemployment insurance benefits.
  - 0163. Union Shop Law. 238 pages., 1950; 11 (Reel 30)
    Major Topics: Congressional hearings on amendments to the Railway Labor Act; A. Philip Randolph's statement before the House Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce on the union shop bill; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman union shop agreements between the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and the Pullman Company, between the New York Central System and the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, between the Indiana Harbor Belt Railroad and the Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen of America, between the Monogohela Railway Company and the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, and between the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and the Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad Company.
  - 0401. Union Shop Proposals (Pullman and All Carriers). 6 pages., 1951; 12 (Reel 30)
    Union Shop agreement between the Indiana Harbor Belt Railroad and the Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen of America.
  - 0407. Vacation and Holiday Movement. 6 pages., 1959; 13 (Reel 30)
    Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters proposals regarding vacations and holidays.
  - 0413. Wage Stabilization Board. 38 pages., 1951; 14 (Reel 30)
    Major Topics: Establishment of Temporary Emergency Railroad Wage Panel; report on wage increases for Pullman nonoperating employees; agreement between the Pullman Company and its clerical, office, station, and storehouse employees represented by the Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman agreement regarding pay rates; wage increase agreement between the Pullman Company and its laundry employees represented by the United Transport Services Employees.
  - 0451. Wage Stabilization Board. 25 pages., 1952; 15 (Reel 30)
    Major Topic: Orders and regulations issued by the Wage Stabilization Board and the Salary Stabilization Board.
  - 0476. Washington Job Protection Agreement (Brotherhood's Affiliation). 11 pages., 1961; 16 (Reel 30)
    Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters request for inclusion as party to the Washington Job Protection Agreement.
  - 0487. Welfare Benefits. 10 pages., 1955; 17 (Reel 30)
    Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters application for services of the National Mediation Board on the health and welfare benefits case.
  - 0497. Workmen's Compensation Act. 47 pages., 1941; 18 (Reel 30)
    Major Topic: Colorado workmen's compensation act.
  - 0544. Adams, J.J. - Chicago District, Personal Injury. 3 pages., 1966; 19 (Reel 30)
  - 0547. Arnold, E. Jr. - Chicago District, Personal Injury. 8 pages., 1966; 20 (Reel 30)
  - 0555. Eufre, P.C. - Chicago Commissary District, Personal Injury. 7 pages., 1966; 21 (Reel 30)
  - 0562. Gaines, Houston - Personal Injury. 6 pages., 1966; 22 (Reel 30)
  - Jackson, O.W. - Personal Injury, 3 pages., 1966; 23 (Reel 30)
  - Torry, J.P. - Personal Injury. 2 pages., 1966; 24 (Reel 30)
  - 0573. National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. 75 pages., 1969-1970; 25 (Reel 30)
    Major Topics: Report on the history of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; report on election of National Association for the Advancement of Colored People officers; report on National Association for the Advancement of Colored People urban program in Chicago; financial statements for the Southside Chicago Branch of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; minutes of Illinois State National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Conference.
  - 0648. National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. 101 pages., 1971; 26 (Reel 30)
    Major Topics: National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Political Action Committee report; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People economic, political action, housing, and educational surveys; report on election of National Association for the Advancement of Colored People officers; financial statements for the Southside Chicago Branch of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; benefits for black veterans; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People positions on the My Lai incident in Vietnam and on employment discrimination; agenda for meeting of the Executive Committee of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Southside Chicago Branch; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People demand for minimum wage legislation in Illinois; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People code of personnel and employment practices.
  - 0749. National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. 110 pages., 1972-1977; 27 (Reel 30)
    Major Topics: National Association for the Advancement of Colored People membership campaign; financial statement for the Southside Chicago Branch of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; reports of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Legal Office; reports on National Association for the Advancement of Colored People urban program in Chicago; agenda and minutes for National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Executive Committee meetings; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People opposition to moratorium on busing to achieve school integration.
  - 0859. A. Philip Randolph Institute. 106 pages., 1967-1971; 28 (Reel 30)
    Major Topics: 1970 Senate elections; civil rights movement and the trade unions; report on the failure of black separatism; report on the future of the civil rights movement; recommendations of the National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence; report on black youth; report on feminism; report on the power of the black vote; report on civil rights strategy for the 1970s.